

This document was generated from a webpage.

Visit www.scottvincent.ca to view complete portfolio & examples.

contact@scottvincent.ca 519.694.5254

LONDON, ONTARIO, CANADA

Story

Front End Designer with work seen on over 1 Billion pageviews. (Yep, Billion)

Experienced in graphic design, user interfaces, front end development, product design, project management, quality assurance. I want the users of the product to love the results as much as I do. I believe putting care into the finest details along the way results in a final product that exceeds expectations.

In high school I started to get into Adobe Photoshop, Final Cut Pro and went into a 2 year TV Broadcasting program. At the same time as being apart of the daily live news program, I was gaining more experience in live auditorium audio and lighting systems in a theatre setting. The passion for video shooting & editing almost landed me in TV Broadcasting, but at the last minute I decided to try something new and go into Multimedia Design & Production at Fanshawe College. After completing the two year diploma I got accepted into Music Industry Arts, and took my love of music to the studio setting. I've been lucky enough to have learned from some talented professionals, gaining valuable knowledge.

During my professional career I was a part of many projects in a wide variety of industries. Staying on top of current web trends and technology has been the key to continued success. I have experience with languages and frameworks such as HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, LESS, SASS, AMP, Bootstrap, Font Awesome, Google Material Design, & AngularJS. Speed and proficiency in programs such as Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Avid Pro Tools, & Apple Logic Pro.

Being able to do anything that is necessary in a project gives me the flexibility to keep the job fresh and interesting.

Experience

IES Group Inc.

Graphic / Web / Product Designer, UI/UX Lead, Front End Developer

4/2011 - 10/2016

London, ON

Design & develop web application interfaces, user experience, logo illustration, branding materials, & marketing collateral.

OUR Coffee News Graphic / Web Designer

1/2009 - 7/2011

St. Thomas, ON

Update and maintain website, Create ad samples to be placed in the weekly restaurant publication. Setup and print editions with one colour process.

Stiches Above

CNC Machine Operator

6/2005 - 12/2008

London, ON

A multi-head CNC machine operator for a custom embroidery company. The job consisted of unpacking, prepping, and embroidering items, such as hats, coats, & shirts.

Education

Fanshawe College Music Industry Arts

2008 - 2010

- School of Contemporary Media Diploma
- 2009 MIA Award, Best Performance

Fanshawe College Multimedia Design & Production

2006 - 2008

School of Contemporary Media Diploma

H.B. Beal Secondary School

2002 - 2006

- OSSD Diploma, Ontario Scholar
- 2 year Television Broadcasting
- 2006 Most Co-operative Student Award
- 2005 Skills Canada Video Challenge,
 Ontario Bronze Medal

Web Projects

Scott Vincent Design

The site you're currently on is an exercise in lightweight web design. Utilizing Google's Accelerated Mobile Pages guidelines, it ensures incredibly quick page load times. AMP is a validation specification that combats the bloated and inconsiderate web. Currently it's become commonplace to add large libraries and heavy dependancies to accomplish fairly simple tasks. This is about getting down to what really is the problem you are trying to solve with a website, without punishing users with data and loading times.

This site loads less than **500KB** onto your device to deliver all its information and imagery. Along with the shear speed in which it loads, it still takes into consideration the browser size and device type to deliver a responsive user friendly experience.

Media Sonar

Media Sonar is a social media monitoring tool used for public safety and law enforcement. I was a part of the project from 2013 to 2016. After working on the first version of the application briefly in 2013, I was brought on as the Lead Designer for the version 2 refresh at the end of 2014. Prototyping, designing, and styling the front-end for a positive user experience.

An AngularJS web app, Bootstrap 3 was the base styling framework used to build it fully responsive to fit any screen size. Using Google's Material Design Guidelines as a starting point, eventually the design language transformed away from that core to meet the needs of the business. Utilizing LESS css, I created a variable styling structure that allows multiple colour themes for users to switch between, as well as modular components for fast prototyping and delivery.

Diply

Diply was an entertainment website that I worked on from 2013 to the end of 2014. Created initially as a online product showcase, it morphed into articles to be shared on social media.

Half of the 2 man team that built the initial site with Bootstrap 3, and leveraging LESS css. Diply was an Angular web application with a custom content management system. I was the Lead UI Designer during the site's first year, responsible for prototyping, front-end styling, and user experience. From launch over the next year I was there, those pages were viewed over 1 billion times.

G₂PO

A gaming video site I worked on as designer and front end developer thorugh the evolution of two distinct versions in 2011 and 2014. It gave users options to search and follow video creators or specific game titles and view videos on the site.

Responsive for mobile web use, built with Bootstrap 2 and C# .NET.

Baitclick

In response to the experience in looking behind the curtain of social sharing methods, a desire to build something to stand up to the clickbait machine was formed. A site where you paste links that pose a question, spoil the title, and share that insight with your friends. Saving them from the temptation to click on those links. Practicing simple user experience with a unique, fun idea was the goal after years of working on complicated, serious applications.

Co-founder of this 2 man project not released to the public yet, this site is built with MEAN.js framework along with Bootstrap 3, and LESS css. Features include Day/Night modes, automatic image creation, and mobile specific UI.

Branding

One of my favourite activities is to think about branding.

When a major brand makes a change, I'm usually disecting what they've done and why. I will read branding blogs daily to see what companies are doing and what the design community thinks of current trends. I have such an attention to detail, I usually pick apart when brands are being misused in the wild or if they're nailing it with little fanfare.

I enjoy designing & constructing new things in Adobe Illustrator, whether it is for startups, bands, or even recreational sports teams. The collection of logos I've created, some turned into large companies, some never got off the ground, and some of these were created and never used.

Music

Audio Engineer, Music Producer, & Guitarist

Music has always been a part of my life, starting on guitar at 10 years old, I would go on to play in the bands Violet Fuse & Duelling Sledgehammers.

I graduated from Music Industry Arts at Fanshawe College in 2010, gaining proficiency in Avid Pro Tools, Avid D-Command interface, analog recording consoles, Logic Pro, and music production techniques.